<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SubToMe Docs</title>
    <link>http://docs.subtome.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://docs.subtome.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <atom:link href="http://pubsubhubbub.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description></description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 10:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 10:16:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>

    
    
    <item>
      <title>FlowReader supports SubToMe</title>
      <link>http://docs.subtome.com/2014/09/19/flowreader/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://docs.subtome.com/2014/09/19/flowreader</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://flowreader.com&quot;&gt;FlowReader&lt;/a&gt; is a web-based personal news reader that offers a new way to browse online content, combining RSS feeds along with links and stories shared on Facebook and Twitter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can combine your Facebook, Twitter and Google account to extract content from all of them and then categorize, filter and read what you care about most. This is very handy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From today, if you’re a FlowReader user, everytime you’ll see a SubToMe button, like on a &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/04/13/subtome-in-feedburner/&quot;&gt;Feedbuner feed&lt;/a&gt;, for example, you’ll be redirected to FlowReader!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Wordpress Reader with SubToMe</title>
      <link>http://docs.subtome.com/2014/06/23/wordpress-reader-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://docs.subtome.com/2014/06/23/wordpress-reader-support</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever visited a Wordpress.com hosted blog, you’ve probably noticed that there are multiple buttons to follow that blog by email or using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt; reader. Now, if your blog is not hosted on Wordpress, you can easily &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.subtome.com/publishers/&quot;&gt;add a SubToMe button&lt;/a&gt; to your site so that more people follow it from their wordpress reader!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you use the Wordpress reader to follow your favorite sources of content online, you should add the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.subtome.com/#/settings&quot;&gt;SubToMe bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; (or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/subtome/cjkhnlmkkfheepafpgppmpdahbjgkjfc?hl=en&quot;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/subtome-subscribe-button/&quot;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; addons) so that you can easily add our favorite sites to follow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for those who wonder, yes, this happened at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.subtome.com/2014/05/21/reboot-rss/&quot;&gt;Reboot RSS workshop&lt;/a&gt;! Our community can get so much done, much faster, when we know each other! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy following!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebooting feeds</title>
      <link>http://docs.subtome.com/2014/05/21/reboot-rss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://docs.subtome.com/2014/05/21/reboot-rss</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The current &lt;em&gt;specifications for RSS and Atom are old&lt;/em&gt; by the web standards and have not evolved in a long time. Yet, the way feeds are produced and consumed certainly has evolved. The &lt;strong&gt;reading experiences&lt;/strong&gt; outside of RSS have evolved.  It’s time to reconcile things!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.superfeedr.com/&quot;&gt;Superfeedr&lt;/a&gt;, we’re convinced that one of the most important things to work on is to ease the subscription process. There are &lt;a href=&quot;http://julien.svbtle.com/follow-buttons-everywhere&quot;&gt;follow buttons everywhere&lt;/a&gt; and more than ever &lt;em&gt;content discovery needs to happen outside of search engines&lt;/em&gt;. Yet, feeds are left on the side of the road when it comes to that. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.subtome.com/&quot;&gt;SubToMe&lt;/a&gt; is an effort at fixing that in a &lt;strong&gt;decentralized, open and privacy-aware&lt;/strong&gt; way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In June, we will be at the “Reboot RSS” workshop and we’ll pitch that idea. We’ve heard from other people involved in the RSS world that they’re interested in seeing the &lt;strong&gt;formats&lt;/strong&gt; evolve (maybe even JSON). Some other are interested in having &lt;strong&gt;better analytics&lt;/strong&gt; mechanisms built in the feeds so that publishers have a better visibility on what happens to their content in the feeds they publish… Similarly, some asked for things like &lt;a href=&quot;http://indiewebcamp.com/webmention&quot;&gt;Webmentions&lt;/a&gt; endpoints made available in feeds so people can remotely comment on the content they read… etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in coming, please, email julien@superfeedr.com&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SubToMe in Feedburner</title>
      <link>http://docs.subtome.com/2014/04/13/subtome-in-feedburner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://docs.subtome.com/2014/04/13/subtome-in-feedburner</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, SubToMe has been added to Feedburner! Feedburner is still an incredibly popular RSS feed platform which provides analytics and landing pages for RSS feed owners. It has not been getting a lot of attention form Google since they aquire it, but people still use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re using Feedburner, make sure you allow SubToMe as one of the mechanisms to subscribe to the feed by going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://feedburner.google.com/&quot;&gt;Feedburner’s home page&lt;/a&gt;. Then, in the &lt;strong&gt;Optimize Menu&lt;/strong&gt;, pick &lt;strong&gt;BrowserFriendly&lt;/strong&gt; and click on the &lt;strong&gt;Appearance&lt;/strong&gt; option link. Make sure SubToMe is selected :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check the integration on these feeds for example: &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/Indepthafrica&quot;&gt;Indepthafrica&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/CanadianSecurity&quot;&gt;CanadianSecurity&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/Phase108&quot;&gt;Phase108&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an amazing piece of news, but don’t forget that if you integrate a SubToMe button directly into your site, you’ll get subscription stats, and you can style it in any way you like. Of course &lt;em&gt;SubToMe works really well with any feed&lt;/em&gt;, including your Feedburner feed! This is all completely transparent to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy subscribing!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SubToMe and the Open Web</title>
      <link>http://docs.subtome.com/2014/03/17/subtome-openweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://docs.subtome.com/2014/03/17/subtome-openweb</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am convinced that the web is currently &lt;em&gt;crippled&lt;/em&gt; in many ways compared to the closed silos which are Android, iOS, but also the giant platforms like Google+, Facebook or Twitter. The web has an incredible set of advantages compared to this plaform: the distributed-ness, the ubiquity, the lack of gatekeeper… etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, in 2014, the open web is much harder to use on many many levels than these plaforms and that’s what we should address first. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;following&quot;&gt;Following&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following someone on a silo is often as easy as hitting a basic &lt;strong&gt;“Follow” button&lt;/strong&gt;. Twitter does that extremely well, but Facebook, G+ and &lt;a href=&quot;http://julien.svbtle.com/follow-buttons-everywhere&quot;&gt;everybody else do it&lt;/a&gt;. The problem is obvious: there is a &lt;em&gt;strong coupling&lt;/em&gt; between the reading platform and the publishing platform: you need a Twitter account to follow me there. Yikes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web itself is an &lt;strong&gt;amazing publishing and reading platform&lt;/strong&gt;, why then, couldn’t we have &lt;em&gt;web scale&lt;/em&gt; buttons to follow sites we like using the tools we pick? This is what &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.subtome.com/#/&quot;&gt;SubToMe&lt;/a&gt; does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-ness&quot;&gt;Open-ness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you’re questioning SubToMe’s openness. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first, easy (yet skewed) answer would be to send you to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/superfeedr/subtome/&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt;: it’s all in there, accessible to anyone for read and write: you can (and should) submit pull requests to make it better as some others have done in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, its openess is also guaranteed by the fact that it’s &lt;strong&gt;server-less&lt;/strong&gt;. Most silos are probably built by good people. Yet, the economics of these silos are such that they need to lock your data in order to scale. Twitter needs to keep track of what you read if they want to show you relevant ads, Google needs to keep track of what you’re looking for to show you other ads… and paying services also have an incentive to lock you down if they want to guarantee their revenue stream (I’m looking at you, LinkedIn!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.subtome.com/#/&quot;&gt;SubToMe&lt;/a&gt; is not like that: it does not run on a server, but in &lt;strong&gt;your&lt;/strong&gt; browser, fully. The consequence is that it’s completey free to run (except for the domain name hosting), and scales extremely well. Even when hundreds of milions of people use the button, the cost of making it available is the cost of bandwidth spent to download its &lt;em&gt;couple  KiloBytes once&lt;/em&gt;. This means, that there will &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; be a need for SubToMe to charge or put ads in front of its users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, not only not being open would be &lt;strong&gt;technically challenging&lt;/strong&gt;, but it would also be &lt;strong&gt;economically difficult to sustain&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;then-why-do-you-care&quot;&gt;Then why do you care?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When somebody claims they’re doing &lt;strong&gt;the right thing&lt;/strong&gt;, it’s mandatory to ask them what it their motive. After all, these silos are profitable businesses and they pay their employees significantly as well. Why not do the same?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I’m &lt;strong&gt;not into growing a slice, but into growing a pie&lt;/strong&gt;. I am convinced that these silos are growing at the expense of the rest of the web. As time passes, we visit less and less different websites. And these few websites are probably receiving an increasing share of the total web’s revenues. My bet is that the web, like nature is stronger when there is more diversity, and I’d argue that the &lt;strong&gt;webdiversity&lt;/strong&gt; is currently going down, exactly like its natural counterpart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://superfeedr.com/&quot;&gt;My business&lt;/a&gt; is also based on the amount of webdiversity. In a &lt;em&gt;distributed world, it’s hard to collect data from thousands or milions of different sites&lt;/em&gt; and the need for services like &lt;a href=&quot;https://superfeedr.com/&quot;&gt;Superfeedr&lt;/a&gt; exists. I believe our insterests in terms of open-ness is perfectly aligned with our business interest, which is why we picked open protocols for our API, and why we’re doing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.subtome.com/#/&quot;&gt;SubToMe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Call to action</title>
      <link>http://docs.subtome.com/2014/01/06/call-to-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://docs.subtome.com/2014/01/06/call-to-action</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that there is a &lt;em&gt;violent attention race&lt;/em&gt; in today’s web. Keeping the user focused is extremely hard and every possible context switching will be used by the users to open a new tab to check their emails, Twitter or Google News. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you write great content for the web and your readers avidly read all your stories. Yet, when they reach the end of blog post, they’re left to themselves: not sure about what they should do next. And that’s exactly at &lt;em&gt;that time that they’ll switch tabs, apps or click away&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, it’s also once they’ve started learning about you, once they’ve decided they’re interested in your content that you should make sure you let them decide if they want more: offer them easily &lt;strong&gt;actionable buttons&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;em&gt;follow&lt;/em&gt; your content!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the reason why we put &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.subtome.com/&quot;&gt;SubToMe&lt;/a&gt; buttons at the end of our blog posts, and why our &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org/plugins/subtome/&quot;&gt;Wordpress plugin&lt;/a&gt; now has an option to include a button at the end of each post!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Attributes</title>
      <link>http://docs.subtome.com/2013/12/09/data-attributes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://docs.subtome.com/2013/12/09/data-attributes</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, I met &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrisvanpatten.com/&quot;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; and we had a great discussion on how to improve SubToMe by supporting &lt;code&gt;data-*&lt;/code&gt; attributes on the buttons. This is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/html/wg/drafts/html/master/#custom&quot;&gt;HTML5 spec&lt;/a&gt; which enables developers to embed data along with its related DOM element. This is exactly how SubtoMe should be designed as per &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/superfeedr/subtome/issues/60&quot;&gt;Chris comments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using different feeds for &lt;strong&gt;multiple buttons&lt;/strong&gt; has been a pretty common feature request. No later than last week, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.evilprofessor.co.uk/&quot;&gt;LLoyd&lt;/a&gt; asked for it. Even though it is possible without the data attributes, it involves a lot more Javascript and is significantly less elegant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, each SubToMe button can be configured to specify what are the resources being susbcribed to, as well as the feeds. The button can also be used to include a &lt;em&gt;recommended tool&lt;/em&gt; for the subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check the &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.subtome.com/publishers/&quot;&gt;publisher documentation&lt;/a&gt; if you want to see how this can be setup for your buttons very easily!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved SubToMe Widget</title>
      <link>http://docs.subtome.com/2013/12/03/improved-wordpress-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://docs.subtome.com/2013/12/03/improved-wordpress-plugin</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://notizblog.org/&quot;&gt;Matthias&lt;/a&gt; just pushed an update to the SubToMe wordpress plugin. This update brings a lot of great features for anyone with a Wordpress.org blog: &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org/plugins/subtome/&quot;&gt;install it now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it brings more &lt;em&gt;customization&lt;/em&gt; to the button itself: you can easily change its look, as well as configure the text around it. You can now pick between a regular HTML button, or the SubToMe logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most importantly, you can now also include the button in more than just the side bar. Sidebar widgets are great, but they’re also out of the flow. This version introduces the ability to put the &lt;strong&gt;button at the bottom of each post&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit if that if the user has appreciated the post they just read, it’s now simple to just hit the button and subscribe using their favorite tool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also add the button on &lt;em&gt;pages&lt;/em&gt;, or even on &lt;em&gt;lists of posts&lt;/em&gt; like search results, archive or the home page. Finally, and that’s for the most advanced users, the plugins introduces a &lt;a href=&quot;http://codex.wordpress.org/Shortcode_API&quot;&gt;shortcode&lt;/a&gt; to be integrated in completely custom layouts or &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; posts themselves! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org/plugins/subtome/&quot;&gt;Install the SubToMe Plugin for Wordpress now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Counting Subscribers</title>
      <link>http://docs.subtome.com/2013/11/25/counting-subscribers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://docs.subtome.com/2013/11/25/counting-subscribers</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right or wrong, the &lt;strong&gt;amount of “followers”&lt;/strong&gt; is often used as a proxy for &lt;em&gt;popularity&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;importance&lt;/em&gt;. We believe this is the reasons why &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feedburner.com/‎&quot;&gt;Feedburner&lt;/a&gt; quickly got so popular: it gave publishers and bloggers an interesting metric that they could compare. Years later, the number of followers on Twitter is also prominent on &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.twitter.com/docs/follow-button&quot;&gt;their follow buttons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, since SubToMe is fully &lt;strong&gt;decentralized&lt;/strong&gt; (publishing applications and subscribing applications are unaware of each other), it’s really hard to provide accurate analytics (not that Feedburner’s stats were accurate either… but that’s another story). However, there is one thing that SubToMe can tell the publisher: that a &lt;em&gt;susbcription happened&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, everytime someone clicks on the SubToMe button you’ve put on your site, SubToMe will &lt;em&gt;trigger a Javascript event&lt;/em&gt; that you should listen to. The event incldues the following information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;feeds&lt;/strong&gt;: the list of feeds to which the user may have subscribed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;resource&lt;/strong&gt;: the HTTP resource related to the subscription&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The app&lt;/strong&gt; used to subscribe: its name and its url.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some sample code:
&lt;code&gt;
  window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;, function(event) {
    if (event.origin !== &quot;https://www.subtome.com&quot;)
    return;
    // do something with event.data.subscription
  });
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.subtome.com/load.js&quot;&gt;load.js&lt;/a&gt; file, which is the default way to load the SubToMe button, will also trigger a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/analytics/&quot;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt; (if your site uses it) event to tell you that somebody subscribed to your feed! &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful integrations</title>
      <link>http://docs.subtome.com/2013/11/22/custom-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://docs.subtome.com/2013/11/22/custom-integration</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the key design goals behind SubToMe is to make it as open as possible. To achieve that, we make sure that SubToMe is only built using HTML, CSS and Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key benefit of that approach is that you can easily tweak SubToMe to make it fit your design!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are three websites which did a great job:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christophh.net/#&quot;&gt;http://www.christophh.net/&lt;/a&gt;: a beautiful flat design button. Hard to not click to get more!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://continuations.com/&quot;&gt;http://continuations.com/&lt;/a&gt;: nice integration in the top menu bar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.izs.me&quot;&gt;http://blog.izs.me&lt;/a&gt;: each post ends with an invitation to send an email or follow this blog. Nice call to action!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you put a SubToMe button on your site? Let us know in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://docs.subtome.com/2013/10/08/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://docs.subtome.com/2013/10/08/hello-world</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the new documentation site for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.subtome.com/#/&quot;&gt;SubToMe&lt;/a&gt;. It will include general documentation for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.subtome.com/publishers/&quot;&gt;publishers&lt;/a&gt; who implemented the button, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.subtome.com/developers/&quot;&gt;readers&lt;/a&gt; who are able to handle these subscriptions as well as news related to SubToMe: new releases, interesting implementations, goodies… etc.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    

  </channel>
</rss>
